Zaki Salleh



PROFILE

Born Malaysian and raised in the slow-paced Shah Alam, I spent a substantial amount of time growing up in Dhaka, Bangladesh. My first exposure to design was in Dhaka when I was 12. I stumbled across a 3d modelling community first as a lurker, and eventually started participating in the monthly challenges. Soon enough, I started submitting some works into the community-sponsored competitions, and won my first one when I was 13.

Fast forward a few years later, I return to Malaysia, and received my major degree in Graphic Design along with a minor degree in Automotive Design that I did at the same time. By graduation, I had gained several recognitions from the university including the prestigious Vice-Chancellor Awards, and the Best Student Awards from two different campuses — UiTM Seri Iskandar (Diploma), and UiTM Shah Alam (Degree).

Today, after about five years working as a product designer, I've grown from a primarily visual designer into a more full-fledged UX designer with experience developing (and launching) products at scale on the web. Some of the responsibilities I've held as a product designer include overseeing the entire development process of a product—from brand exploration and visual design to design research, prototyping, and product testing. I've also worked on products at scale where working closely with the product managers, developers, and stakeholders, we built and launched a production-ready MVP, and grew it to more than 15 thousand active users in the first month by delivering weekly iterations based on user feedback and experiments that we run. This tight feedback loop enabled us to quickly deliver values to our users.

As a designer, I'm quite reserved, but have been described as a critical thinker. I'm comfortable working in both small and big teams—locally, or remotely—and collaborating closely with my team to arrive at a design solution that realises our vision while delivering real value to our customers.

EXPERIENCE

DESIGNER, ATLASSIAN; SYDNEY 2015 - PRESENT

Joined as a designer on Confluence before moving on to Bamboo and joined the team that eventually developed a cloud-focused CI solution called Bitbucket Pipelines. Worked closely with the product managers and front-end developers to run design research and rapid experiments to test out ideas. As part of a cross-geo team (the majority of the Bitbucket team is based in SF), I worked with my design mentor to develop a documentation system that increases visibility of our design works and helps us align our work.

UX DESIGNER, VLT LABS; KUALA LUMPUR 2013 - 2015

Led design for our clients, most of which were early-stage startups. Their early stage meant we had a pretty broad scope of work including brand development, user research, UI design, prototyping, and product testing. As part of the process, I also facilitated various workshops and design sprints with the stakeholders—which includes product owners and developers—to identify key goals for their products, and narrow down on features to build for the MVP.

DESIGNER, VLT; KUALA LUMPUR 2012 - 2013

Worked with some of the biggest brands in Malaysia including Astro and Kleenex. I was responsible for the experience and visual design of our client's online apps and campaigns, as well as some pitching jobs which included wireframing, and mocking up conceptual website designs. I also helped maintain retainer accounts with items like icon designs, and content updates. In certain cases, I work with the developers to maintain web contents for some retainer accounts.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITI TEKNOLOGI MARA, SHAH ALAM — DEGREE, 2012

- · Vice Chancellor's Award
- Outstanding Student Award (Department of Graphic Design

UNIVERSITI TEKNOLOGI MARA, SERI ISKANDAR — DIPLOMA, 2010

- · Vice Chancellor's Award
- Outstanding Student Award (Faculty of Art and Design)
- Outstanding Student Award (Department of Graphic Design)

SKILLS

User experience design, visual design, design research and validation, rapid prototyping with supportive skills in HTML, CSS, and JS and an basic understanding of modern web development technologies.